degreed.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy Policy | Degreed

Last Updated: February 2019

Version number: 4.0

Degreed, Inc. ("Degreed") is committed to respecting the privacy of its users. We strive to provide a safe, secure online experience. This Privacy Policy sets forth the online data collection, usage, maintenance, disclosure and protection policies and practices that apply when personal information is disclosed in connection with the Degreed.com website and applications (together: "Site") and the services provided through it, such as our Degreed learning platform ("Services"). We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other websites to which links are included on this Site. 

### Consent and Revisions to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time as we add new features or as laws change that may affect our Site or Services. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will let you know in an appropriate manner and we will post a new version number at the beginning of this Privacy Policy, consisting of the date (year and month) the Privacy Policy was last revised, so that you will be able to tell when the Privacy Policy was last changed.

### What Information is Collected

We collect and process personal information about you when you interact with us and our Services. Such information may include:

  * Your name, email address, username and password;
  * Your academic history and other information you entered into your User profile ("Degreed Profile"), and how you use our Services;
  * Your marketing preferences, including any consents you have given us; and
  * Information related to the browser or device you use to access our Site, as also further detailed in our Cookie Policy.

Most personal information you provide to us is voluntary, unless indicated otherwise. Examples of areas on the Site where we collect data are pages where you can open a Degreed account and create a Degreed Profile. Only you can modify your own personal Degreed Profile once it has been created. You may remove your Degreed Profile from our database at any time. To the extent you wish to retain an independent record of such your Degreed Profile, you must include a personal email address at the time of creating your Degreed Profile.

We may combine the information we collect with publicly available information and information we receive from our parent, affiliate, or subsidiary companies, business partners, and other third parties. We may use that combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us, to communicate with you about products, services, and events that may be of interest to you, for promotional purposes, and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

In addition, if you access and use the Site or the Services on a mobile device and your mobile device's settings allow it, we may collect information about your real-time location. If you access our Services using a mobile device, you may adjust the settings on your mobile device to allow or prevent the sharing of location information. For example, you can disable "Location" (or "Location Services" on iOS-based devices) on your mobile device to prevent sharing your location information with us. Please refer to instructions provided by your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your mobile device to learn how to adjust your mobile device settings. Please note that if you disable the sharing of location information, you may be unable to access some features of our Services that are designed for mobile devices.

We may enable you to log into the Services using a social media account, and if you do so you may be asked to grant us access to certain information from your social media profile, such as your public profile, birthday, current city, and e-mail address. Social media networks operate independently from Degreed, and we are not responsible for social media networks' interfaces or privacy or security practices. Please refer to the privacy settings of the applicable social media platform or application to determine how you may manage the interactivity between us and your social media account.

### How Information is Used

We process your personal information for the following purposes:

  * As required to provide you with our Services and establish and fulfill our contract with you. This may include verifying your identity, communicating with you and providing customer services;
  * As required by us to enable our business and pursue our legitimate interests, in particular:
    * we monitor the use of our Site and Services, and may use your information to help us monitor, improve and protect our products, content, services and websites, both online and offline;
    * we may use information you provide to personalize our Site and Services for you;
    * we may monitor our Services to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime, in accordance with applicable laws;
    * we may use information you provide to investigate any complaints received from you or from others;
    * we may use your information to invite you to take part in market research; and
  * As required for compliance with applicable laws and protection of Degreed's legitimate business interests and legal rights, including, but not limited to, use in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, investigative purposes (including disclosure of such information in connection with legal process or litigation).

In addition, and where needed with your consent, we may send you messages in relation to our products and services, for example to send notifications about new features. You can opt-out of such messages by following the instructions in the communication.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Anonymous Information

Where possible, the Degreed servers automatically recognize each User's Internet Protocol address. Also, aggregate information about Degreed Users is routinely gathered for purposes of identifying the use of Degreed.com, including information such as what pages are being visited most, what domains our visitors are coming from (i.e. google.com), when our servers are busiest, and what websites are referring Users to us and aggregated data for purposes of analysis, gathering employment statistical information and for learning and training. This information helps us to improve our services and to evaluate our marketing efforts. We only use such data anonymously and aggregately. This information may be shared with third parties, but only in the aggregate. The treatment of non-personally identifiable information is subject to change in accordance with the then applicable law. Degreed owns all rights in and to this anonymous and aggregated data.

### Sharing Information with Third Parties and International Transfer

If necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy we can share your information with other Degreed entities or third-party service providers, for example email and hosting providers, payment processing providers, customer management providers and marketing providers. Such third-party service providers will process your information on behalf of Degreed and for the purposes listed above. When we share your data with these parties, we make sure that appropriate safeguards are taken to protect your information.

As we are a global company headquartered in the United States, we handle data transfers to and from countries with differing levels of protection requirements for personal information. We have taken various measures to ensure adequate protection of such transfers. These safeguards include: 

  * Privacy Shield certifications ([read more here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en) and below in this Privacy Policy)
  * GDPR compliance ([read more here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-protection-eu_en))
  * Applying the EU Commission approved standard contractual clauses ([read more here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en))
  * Adhering to the Binding Corporate Rules some of our providers have in place ([read more here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/binding-corporate-rules_en)).

If you would like to learn more about these safeguards, our contact details are listed near the end of this document.

We reserve the right to transfer your personal information to a buyer or other transferee in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, sale, or other transfer of some or all of our assets. Should such a sale, merger, or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use your personal information in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy.

We may also share your data with other third parties, such as governmental authorities or law enforcement officials, if we are required by law to do so or if this is for the protection of our legitimate interests and/or legal rights.

### Rights of Access, Deletion and Other Rights

We provide you with access to your information through your Degreed Profile, where you can access, update, amend or correct inaccuracies on information provided in your Degreed Profile. From each Degreed account, you may also opt out of receiving newsletters and certain other correspondence from Degreed. If you wish to delete your Degreed Profile, you can do so in the Personal section of their Profile Settings. Once you have arrived at the Profile Settings page, you can select "Delete Profile" and select "yes" to confirm that you would like to delete your account. If you are connected to an enterprise account, you cannot delete your individual account.

In addition to the above, you are entitled to reach out to us via the contact details below and ask us for an overview or copy of your personal information, to correct or delete certain data or restrict processing of your data. In some cases, you may object to the processing of your information and where we have asked you for your consent to process personal information, you can withdraw your consent at any time.

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Services who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [info@degreed.com](mailto:info@degreed.com) or write us at: 445 Bryant Street, San Francisco, CA 94107

Please note that the rights described above are not absolute, and that your request cannot always be met entirely. For example, sometimes we cannot delete or restrict the processing of your information as we may have legal obligations or contractual obligations to keep certain information.

### How Long We Retain Your Data

Where you have a Degreed Profile, we will keep your information for the duration of your use of our Services, and, to the extent permitted, after the end of that relationship for as long as necessary to perform the purposes set out in this notice. Laws may require us to hold certain information for specific periods. In other cases, we may retain data for an appropriate period after any relationship with you ends to protect ourselves from legal claims, or to administer its business.

### Children Under 13 Years of Age

Degreed does not intend to collect information from children under the age of 13 or knowingly allow those individuals to create profiles. All Degreed Profiles stored are for Users ages 13 or older and those seeking higher education who state their age to be 13 years or older. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at [info@degreed.com](mailto:info@degreed.com).

### Degreed's use of Cookies and Similar Technologies

Like most websites, Degreed uses cookies and other similar technologies, such as local storage, to provide a better user experience. These cookies are safe and secure, and do not contain sensitive information. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy.

### Information Protection and Security

When you submit information to Degreed, whether it is name or email, we do our utmost to ensure that information is protected against loss, misuse, alteration, destruction or unauthorized access. Degreed uses standard encryption tools such as SSL (Secure Socket Layer) to help protect personal information and to keep information collected secure. The privacy policies of linked sites may differ from those of Degreed. Degreed is not responsible for any loss or misuse of your username and password.

### Privacy Shield

Degreed complies with both the EU-U.S. and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. Degreed has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Degreed is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Degreed complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, the UK and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Degreed is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. Degreed will not use User personal Degreed Profile information except as described above, or as otherwise provided by law. In certain situations, Degreed may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We disclose information if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property of our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 

We provide Users with 24-hour access to their Degreed Profile after input by the applicable User. Users may also wish to amend or correct inaccuracies on information provided in the Degreed Profile. If a User wishes to correct such inaccuracies or make any other changes, that User's Degreed Profile can be accessed through our password protected access facility at https://degreed.com. Any information gathered is to the best of our knowledge collected lawfully and fairly through Degreed.com and all information is assumed accurate and up to date and only information which is adequate and not excessive to our purpose for collection is retained. Users may review, correct, update or change their Degreed Profile and the information therein at any time. From each Degreed account, Users may also opt out of receiving newsletters and certain other correspondence from Degreed. If a User wishes to delete his or her Degreed Profile, that User can do so in the Personal section of their Profile Settings. Once the User has arrived at the Profile Settings page the User can select "Delete Profile" and select "yes" to confirm that the User would like to delete his or her account. If a User is connected to an enterprise account, the User should direct any requests to the learning contact at their company. 

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Degreed commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement should first contact Degreed Support at: 

Degreed  
445 Bryant St.  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
1-800-311-7061  

Degreed has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, JAMS Privacy Shield Dispute Resolution. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information and to file a complaint. 

Finally, as a last resort and under limited circumstances, EU and Swiss individuals with residual privacy complaints in relation to adherence to these Privacy Shield Principles may invoke a binding arbitration option before the Privacy Shield Panel. 

### Contact Details

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or any questions, complaints or claims, please contact us at:

Email: [info@degreed.com](mailto:info@degreed.com)  
Address: 445 Bryant St.  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
Phone: 1-800-311-7061  

We always enjoy hearing from you and appreciate your business. Should you nonetheless have unresolved concerns, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority.
